in this exercise we're given some code
and asked to refactor it to get rid of
repetition
specifically we have a repeated call to
this random number between function
along with incrementing this tries
variable on line six and seven and lines
10 and 11.
if we zoom out and take a take a broad
view of the code what are we trying to
do here
well on line five we are declaring and
initializing the variable tries to zero
on line six we are declaring the
variable result and initializing it to
the return value of calling this random
number between function
if we pop up to lines one through three
we can see that the random number
between is just generating a random
number between a given minimum and
maximum
and then once we call the function we
are incrementing our Triads variable by
one so this first invocation to random
number between represents a single try
on lines 9 through 12 we have a while
loop and this will execute while this
conditional expression returns true so
while result is less than or equal to
two the code within the while loop will
continue to execute
the loop calls the random number between
function in the same manner we did
before and then reassigns the return
value to result tries is Again
incremented by one
and this will keep happening until
result is less than or equal to 2
returns false meaning it will keep going
until result is greater than 2.
finally once we exit the loop on line 14
we are logging how many tries as
represented by the tries variable it
took us to get a result that was greater
than 2.
so simply put what we want to do here is
call random number between at least once
increment tries and then continually do
this until we get a result that meets
our specific criteria in this case a
result that is greater than 2.
so when we have code that we know has to
be executed at least once we can use a
do while loop which will execute the
loop at least once and then continue to
execute it while the conditional we give
to while returns true and this will help
us get rid of the repetitive calls to
random number between an incrementation
so what we want to do here is declare
the result variable without necessarily
initializing it
because this will allow us to utilize it
in the conditional expression then we're
going to move this while bit
down here to the bottom of the loop
because this is where it will get
evaluated and we'll change this to do so
we're going to do this once and then
we'll keep doing it while this is true
and I need to get rid of this repetitive
incrementation as well
so now we have much cleaner less
repetitive code that should have the
exact same functionality and if I run
the code in the terminal just to make
sure it still works which is always a
good idea when you're refactoring I can
see that it took one try to get a number
greater than two so it looks like we are
still good